What is up, guys?
Happy New Year. It's John here from Ads xx
and I'm super excited to just jump on.
Um, it's January 2nd, new me new year.
Hope you guys are stoked about the new year
and have your priorities and goals
and all that stuff you wanna change about yourself
and your business this year lined up.
Um, one of the things
that I'm working on definitely is time management, uh,
prioritization of my schedule
and just being super transparent
and honest to myself about how much time I really have
and how to best leverage the time that I have
and, you know, not get burnt out, keep doing what I'm doing,
keep doing what I love, and also, um, keep building, right?
And while managing family life and stuff.
But nonetheless, uh, I want to actually jump on this video
because I wanted to share, uh, basically how I was able
to create multiple variations of the same ad,
or, sorry, how
to create multiple ad variations from one video shoot.
Um, and I'm gonna share my exact process of doing that
and hopefully you guys can get some inspiration
and apply it to your own businesses, um,
in whatever way you're doing it.
So let's just jump right into it.
Um, I have a little document here that I'll share, uh,
just like outlining the steps, but first
and foremost, the product that we needed ads for was this,
uh, posture corrector.
And so, as you guys probably know,
if you're in the e-com space dropshipping,
like this product is, you know, it's been out forever.
And so we've, we've shot it a ton of times at our studio
and um, or just over the years, uh, just
so many people have, I've have shot this product.
Um, but this client particularly, we had shot some UGC ads
and they didn't work that well.
So I told 'em like, let's see what's out there
and try to replicate it, right?
Because that's kind of my process is to work backwards
with stuff, um, see what's working and then build upon that.
So my first step to finding like
ad inspiration, I'm, I'm a big,
I'm a big believer on like finding what works
and then building off of that.
That's always my rule of thumb is like,
you gotta start somewhere.
Um, and then that kind
of creates the target in which you want to build around.
'cause if you know that's working, then you know, you've,
you've done a lot of the legwork.
They've done a lot of the legwork, right?
So first tip is to search magic brief
or Facebook ad library for ad inspo.
And if you don't have magic brief, I love magic brief.
I think it's just like really well designed.
You obviously have foreplay as well.
Um, two different, they pretty much do the same thing,
but depending on how you're looking up ad
inspiration, it could be any of these three.
It could even be, um,
if you're searching YouTube ads, that kind of stuff too.
So you can type in like, uh, a phrase
and it'll find ads that
have this particular keyword in there, posture corrector.
So you can do it three different ways like this, right?
So you can see that there's a lot of variations here.
Um, and from here, if you have the plugin,
you can save these to your ads, right?
So these are some that I haven't seen yet,
but, um, I'd probably save these to my, to my foreplay.
I'm sorry, my magic brief. Um, and so yeah, same thing here.
All I did was type in back corrector,
or I'm sorry, I went to, um, discover
and I typed in posture corrector
and these ads came up.
Um, I actually didn't find too much.
Let me see if I type in back corrector.
Um, yeah, see, not too much here.
I probably started off, yeah, that's what I did.
So I went to at library
and then from here is where I actually saved,
saved the ads, right?
So, um, the first things I was looking
for obviously is like, what are the hooks?
What are the demos? Um, how long are the videos?
What are people doing, right?
I'm really just inspecting the landscape of, of the,
the ads being run
and then seeing if, um, you know, if we can recreate it
or build upon it, right?
And one of the, the trends that I saw, this girl who,
who's like in every single video,
and I think every single drop shipper is
using this, this clip.
But, um, this is Asian girl who's like super fit,
super thin, and she's wearing super tight clothes.
And, uh, we just turned this down,
but yeah, we basically didn't do this
when we first shot the video.
Um, and we were focusing more on like pain points and stuff.
But what this really like stood out to me was like, dude,
this chick is obviously like hot,
and she's like very like curvy.
And the demo, the, I'm sorry, the demonstration is like,
it's, it's this key demonstration of like moving the,
the thing back, right?
It's like this arching of the back,
like showing the full demonstration there.
So when I watched all these videos, I'm like, okay,
they're all pretty much doing the same thing,
but just a different angle.
So this says something, right? It's working.
If you go to TikTok, um,
and like type in back, uh, posture corrector,
like you're gonna find, like you can find at,
at in info in here as well.
Um,
posture Corrector, I think I typed this in
and then it, uh, a ton of, ton
of these videos came up as well.
Um, but anyways, you can see that probably it's hard
to see on my screen, but there's like 4.9 million views.
Um, this is so lame, lame.
Just let me log in, leave me alone please, TikTok.
Okay, so this one has 61 million views. It's pretty insane.
This guy probably made a s**t ton of money as an affiliate,
uh, 16.9.
So yeah, they're, they're reusing the same ad.
You know, whoever shot this ad, you know,
they're just ripping off the video, um,
which is pretty common.
So anyways, that is, that's for me,
that's enough inspiration to get to get started.
'cause I'm like, all right, I'm,
I'm seeing the landscape here.
I see what we have to recreate.
Um, so after I do that, uh, I create myself a little album
and I start looking at the landscape of different ads.
And as you can see, like a lot
of the same girl is showing up, right?
But, um, there's a lot of interesting ones here.
There's a lot of like different
hooks that I haven't noticed.
And, um, and yeah,
like basically what I did from here was like,
I saved every single one.
So I, I saved every single video.
And then from here I wrote a little mini shot list of like,
I took screenshots of all the, kind of the angles that I'm,
I was looking to shoot, like the side, the back, the front,
you know, I'm having her do this angle, like this,
like stretching motion.
Um, I'm getting pain point shots as well.
I'm getting these like hunchback shots.
Um, this one was really common,
like this guy's sticking his head forward.
So yeah, this was kind of like my general shot list
that I used before production.
Um, and then from there, um, pretty much shoot it, right?
So if you guys have your own studio
or you're working with UGC creators, like you want
to make sure you are sharing your ideas
and the shots that you want to get with them,
or you're doing it in-house.
It's really like your call on that.
But, um, I like to get just like a lot of variations
of the same thing, different angles, just so
that I have a variety of shots, um,
and a lot to use in post.
That's really what it comes down to.
So, uh, we shot two actors about two
and a half hours for this, for this video.
One of the actresses was really sick, so I didn't really get
as much as I wanted from her, but it's all good.
Um, weird where my camera, so
we shot it next, uploading it
and actually created, um, so I shot it in 4K,
so we shot it on an fx, Sony FX three.
And so the, the footage is really like,
it's really big, right?
Uh, but regardless, I created proxy so
my computer can handle it better.
Um, so the next step I did was I modularized the raws.
And if you guys have taken the training, I'm going
through all the footage here
and I'm basically cleaning them up, right?
I'm moving the ins and outs
and I'm just making it as clean as possible.
These are all just individual shots.
Um, these are all obviously pain points, different hooks.
I got him with a shirt without the shirt.
Um, yeah, I got him rotating.
Just a lot of si like similar variations, right?
Like, that's what I'm going for.
And then we got him using the, the posture corrector
in a similar fashion to what the other ads were doing.
And I'm having him rotate 360 degrees,
moving 15 degrees every like, every shot.
Um, so yeah, that way I have a lot of variety,
different angles there.
Um, I'll get to that. I got him with a shirt on.
Like I said, same shots, different variety.
This is all on a backdrop.
I got some interesting hooks here, like before and after.
These were just kind of like coming up on the spot too,
idea wise and, um, kind of worked out.
You know, that's part of the, the fun part about being in
production is when you're actually shooting it, you can,
you know, you don't necessarily have
to follow the shot list 100%.
Like ideas do come up on the job.
So, uh, I would say it's, it's nice
to take action on those when they come up.
Um, these are just kinda like made up as we went.
So who knows how they'll do.
We'll, we're launching 'em up,
we're launching these ads in a couple days
or we're launching 'em today, so we'll see.
Um, anyways, so the next part to this, okay,
Noize raws right now, you take your inspo ads
and place them onto your timeline.
All right? So I downloaded all of my ads,
all my ad examples, and you can see 'em here.
And basically what I did from here to save time for real,
was I took the ads
and I just dropped them straight into my timeline like this.
All right, so what you see here on top
of it, this is like, this is, I just,
I just created the ad over it, right?
So if I just say like, hide all this,
this is the original ad, and then I just traced over it.
All right? This is something that,
I don't know if you guys do this,
but I've been doing this for a long time.
Just one, it saves me time.
I have like the audio and the music already lined up
and I know the ad works to some degree
and it's just, it just helps, um, just makes my life easier.
So what I like to do is just kind
of take it frame by frame, right?
And then build the ad as I go.
And when I have, you know, clips that match it, for example,
up here, lemme see if it's a little easier
to see on your guys' end.
You know, it's like I know where the cuts are,
I can just add my own cuts in there
and boom, I've got myself an ad.
So I basically follow the same ad, but I added my own shots.
And I have three different hooks here,
four different hooks here.
And it was really easy when I
discovered this pancake method.
You know, I'm, I can easily just find my shots that I want
and then click and drag them into my timeline.
Like, so I found that very, very helpful, very quick
to be able to just like, boom, like there's my shot.
Um, I love this.
I could have, I could have organized this further by like,
you know, adding adjustment layers above this.
You know, if I had more time, I, I would, um,
let me just share what I would do there.
Like if I really wanted to, I'd go over here
and move the shots around
and I would call this, um, you know,
demos with shirt or like mail demo plus shirt.
And I would do the same thing, like over here,
change the color to something else, just
so there's a little bit of like a organization aspect
happening here, but, you know, don't have time for that.
So it's a quick and dirty way.
Anyways, so
after building this ad, I'll just play this ad once.
I don't know why that's playing twice.
That's it, that's it. That's the whole ad. I love that.
It's like 15 seconds or so, 16 seconds.
Um, obviously I shot this in raw, so we did a lot,
I did a lot of color correction on this.
If, if you see this footage before, it's like, no bueno,
but I love this.
I have the Instagram safe guide's on.
Um, this is really, really important just
to make sure like all your
titles and stuff are in the frame.
Uh, I actually have a, a logo watermark in here as well.
'cause a lot of people just steal this stuff, to be honest.
And I just, it's better having protection.
Um, at least some protection even though people will rip it.
Um, and then, yeah, I just moved on to the second ad
and the, the, the other ad was this, which you'll see like,
I, I literally just copied the same, same movements here
and took this ad and, and ran with it.
So here's the second variation here.
It's a little laggy right now. Sorry.
And I don't know why my computer's lagging, but it is.
Um, but you can see
here,
ah, actually that's V two, right?
Ah, Uh,
one thing I wanted to mention here is I am using the
animated arrows, the a x ones.
This came super handy.
It's the whole reason why I created these,
because of these like slouching type of videos
to really show off the curvature here.
I love this. Like, I don't even know how to do this outside
of this template.
So, um, say it came super handy.
I'm using, uh, TikTok titles here, ads Orx style.
So it's all, it's all there.
I I'll just play one more
and then wrap it up.
But
yeah, that's it.
13 seconds. I love these short ads, to be honest.
It's like less work in the editing side
and I can get more variations out.
Um, so each one of these have three variations each,
and It's just building upon the inspiration, right?
So if you have access to a studio, if you shoot yourself,
this is a really fun way
and easy way to pump out a lot of different variations
for clients or for yourself.
Um, and, and yeah,
and you're kind of building upon
what's already working out there.
So all in all, uh, we had eight variations
of the ads times three.
You got 24 or so variations.
So eight, eight ad concepts, 24 total variations.
Not bad. I, I spent about, let's say like all,
the whole thing was about probably like five hours, five,
five hours worth of work, five
and a half hours worth of work.
So with production and all that stuff,
I think all in all is like about five and and a half hours.
So yeah,
you guys can accomplish this if you have your own team.
Obviously, if you guys are in completely different niches,
um, you know, if you're not e-comm,
um, it could be different.
But regardless, I think, uh, this is a good strategy to try
for yourself and let me know, let me know how it goes.